payworks.ca 2011-06-26

# Privacy policy for Payworks Payroll Services Canada

Security Procedures  
not just policies

  * Now Available
  * [2011 Payroll Guide](http://www.payworks.ca/download.asp?y=2011&item=Payroll-Guide) (2MB)
  * Events
Sept 10-11, 2011 
Sept 21-25, 2011
Oct 2-3, 2011
Nov 7-8, 2011

Payworks is committed to providing the highest level of security and privacy regarding the collection and use of our online payroll customers' personal information, as well as that of all visitors to our website. Personal information may be collected through the submission of account applications, online banking transactions, or through the use of online financial tools such as interactive calculators. A detailed description of Payworks Privacy Policy is provided below. If you have additional questions regarding the privacy of your personal information, contact us.

### Applicability

Payworks respects and understands your concerns about privacy. Our goal is to provide you with the personal and financial information required to generate payroll and related transactions for your company. We hope that you will find the website useful and we provide you with this notice of our policy with respect to the information we may collect from you while you are using this site. Additionally, certain aspects of use of this site or information collected through this site may be covered by our contracts, if any, with customers.

Additionally, certain aspects of use of this site or information collected through this site may be covered by our contracts, if any, with customers.

### Collection and Use of Personal Information

Collection of personal information online is designed to protect access to your personal accounts and to assist in providing you with the products and services you want and need. All personal information collected and stored by Payworks is used for specific business purposes - to protect and administer your personal accounts and transactions, to comply with provincial and federal payroll regulations, and to help better understand your payroll needs in order to design or improve our products and services.

Employing stringent security measures in the collection of your personal information, all Payworks online account applications are submitted to Payworks' secure administration site through an encrypted direct line to the secure database. Once received by Payworks, only approved personnel may open and process the application. Furthermore, auditing mechanisms have been put into place to further protect your information by identifying which employees have accessed and in any way modified-for example, updated or added to-your personal information. 

### Maintenance of Accurate Information

It is in the best interest for you to maintain accurate records concerning your personal information. For this reason, Payworks allows you to update your personal information online, at anytime.

### Personally Identifiable Information

From time to time, we may request information that personally identifies you such as your name, mailing address, email address, telephone number, or other information that can be used to identify you. Payworks is very aware of the sensitive nature of such information and sets the highest standards for confidentiality. We are committed to protecting the privacy of both our corporate clients and the individuals for whom payroll transactions are prepared.

### Use of Cookies

Payworks respects your right to privacy and takes every precaution to provide you with the same level of privacy within our website that you receive through more traditional payroll delivery channels.

In some circumstances, Payworks may use cookies to enhance your experience on our site. A "cookie" is a small data file stored on your computer’s hard drive. Cookies allow us to recognize who you are when you arrive at our site by associating the identification numbers in the cookie with other information you, as a site visitor, have provided us. Cookies also tell us how you click to our site and what pages you click on during your visit. You may manage the use of cookies set by our site by changing your browser’s settings, though this may affect your ability to view or interact with certain pages on our site.

### Statistical Information

We collect statistical information based on your use of the website. This information does not identify you personally and is collected for the purpose of maintaining the website and improving its usability.

### Third-Party Disclosure Restrictions

Payworks follows strict privacy procedures in regard to protecting your personal information. In addition, Payworks requires all third parties with a business need to access this information to adhere to similar and equally stringent privacy policies. Personal information may be supplied to a third party in order to process a customer transaction; if the customer requests it; the disclosure is required or allowed by law (i.e. exchange of information with reputable reporting agencies, subpoena, or the investigation of fraudulent activity, etc.); or for marketing purposes of which the customer has been previously informed and has been given the opportunity to decline.

### Dissemination of your Information

Information we receive from you remains your property and is used only for the purposes intended when you enter into an agreement with Payworks. The information is used for no other purpose without express permission from you. Such information is considered confidential and all our employees meet the highest standards of confidentiality. Information is not shared with or transferred to any other corporation, body or individual, in its original or any modified form, unless Payworks is required to do so by statute or legal proceeding, or authorized by you. We limit the information we collect to those personal, financial and financially related details necessary for Payworks to fulfill its contractual obligations to the client. Information gathered from you is kept only for the period of time necessary for Payworks to fulfill its obligations to you.

### Security

Payworks takes the security of your personally identifiable information seriously. We use physical, electronic and operational safeguards designed to reduce the risk of unauthorized access to your personally identifiable information. If you use Payworks web applications, you will select a user ID and password. We strongly recommend that you never divulge these to anyone. All communication through our web applications is encrypted.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. While we strive to protect personally identifiable information, we cannot warrant the security of the personally identifiable information transmitted to or received by us. We provide links to external websites for your convenience. Payworks has no control over the security or privacy practices of these sites. If you have questions regarding a website’s practices, please review that site’s privacy policy.

### Changes to this Policy

Any changes to this policy will be posted at this location and will take effect immediately after their posting. You may wish to check back from time to time to be aware of any changes to the policy.

This Privacy Policy was last updated on 15/10/2008.

Copyright ©2009 Payworks Inc. | 850 Pembina Hwy. Winnipeg, Manitoba, R3M 2M7
